<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Privacy on Grady Berry Ward</title>
    <link>http://gradybward.com/tags/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Privacy on Grady Berry Ward</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gradybward.com/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://gradybward.com/project/creditworthy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradybward.com/project/creditworthy/</guid>
      <description>I just finished reading &amp;ldquo;Creditworthy&amp;rdquo;, Josh Lauer&amp;rsquo;s thorough picture of the history and trajectory of consumer surveillance by the credit industry.
Lauer&amp;rsquo;s work illuminates the early evolution of the social contract at the heart of the information era: convenience, service, and social inclusion in exchange for privacy. Though this exchange is familiar to a twenty first century reader, details from the evolution of this contract (in the context of credit) offer us lessons as we seek to broadly re-negotiate the terms of our privacy forfeitures in all spheres of modern life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://gradybward.com/project/narratives/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradybward.com/project/narratives/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started thinking about how to define privacy. Though I haven&amp;rsquo;t made any traction on that overall question, it&amp;rsquo;s helped me better understand the relationship between privacy and how we manufacture our identity.
To avoid exclusively speaking in intelectualisms, I&amp;rsquo;ll describe the circumstances of my morning, which can illustrate the point I&amp;rsquo;m trying to make.
I went out to get coffee. I usually make coffee at home, but my french press shattered, so I ordered a new one and it was slated for delivery a few days ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://gradybward.com/project/sniff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradybward.com/project/sniff/</guid>
      <description>In _Florida v. Harris_ (2012) a unanimous Supreme Court held that statistically derived evidence of efficacy of a drug sniffing dog was not a requirement for establishing probable cause for evaluating fourth amendment claims. I think this misses the mark from one of my favorite cases _US v. Place_ (1983), in which O&amp;rsquo;Connor issued this gem of straightforward and balanced reasoning:
&amp;ldquo;A &amp;ldquo;canine sniff&amp;rdquo; by a well-trained narcotics detection dog, however, does not require opening the luggage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://gradybward.com/project/terry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradybward.com/project/terry/</guid>
      <description>Terry v. Ohio is known for it&amp;rsquo;s implications on the probable cause requirement of the fourth amendment, but re-reading the decision over the weekend, something else jumped out at me when I put myself in the shoes of the Warren court: given the fact pattern, they were doing their best to encourage good policework, and in the case of stop and frisk the differentiation between &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;bad&amp;rsquo; policing hinges on the quality of the officer&amp;rsquo;s decision making and the outcome of their choice:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>