<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Art on Grady Berry Ward</title>
    <link>http://gradybward.com/tags/art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Art on Grady Berry Ward</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gradybward.com/tags/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://gradybward.com/project/widmanst%C3%A4tten/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradybward.com/project/widmanst%C3%A4tten/</guid>
      <description>When visiting the Smithsonian Natural History Museum, I saw the inside of a meteorite, stained and polished to reveal a beautiful pattern. Several months later, I remembered it while looking through some photos and decided to learn more about it and try to reproduce it.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what I learned from Wikipedia: The meteorites that display this pattern are comprised of of two Iron-Nickel alloys, Kamacite and Taenite. This pattern is found in metiorites called Octahidrites, so named because the pattern is actually a result of a crystal structure of Taenite&amp;rsquo;s crystal latice, which is hexoctahedral (cubic) in structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://gradybward.com/project/cindi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradybward.com/project/cindi/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: Janelle Monae&amp;rsquo;s art inspired me to try to build an algorithm that progamatically generates emotion-evoking art, and the results are here.
If you haven’t yet listened to Janelle Monae’s “Metropolis” suite, I highly recommend that you drop the committments you can, pour yourself some coffee and/or wine, and listen to it carefully.
Monae is a magician, a siren, an entertainer, a theorist, a historian, and a visionary. Metropolis helped me understand so much about so much that talking about it here will certainly do it an injustice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://gradybward.com/project/draw_me_css/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradybward.com/project/draw_me_css/</guid>
      <description>In the third Harry Potter book, Harry is given the “Maurauder’s Map”, and one of the many images I like about this map is how the ink spreads outward from the point that it is awoken.
I wondered if you could do this in CSS, so I poked around, learned about CSS Transitions, and came up with a generalized framework for making a set of boxes animate on to the page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://gradybward.com/project/euclid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradybward.com/project/euclid/</guid>
      <description>Two of my all time favorite books are &amp;ldquo;Measurement&amp;rdquo; by Lockheart and &amp;ldquo;The Elements of Euclid&amp;rdquo; by Byrne. Both take nontraditional approaches to exploring geometry. Part of what is magical about them is the way that they build an intuitive depth that doesn&amp;rsquo;t rely on formalism. This project came to me while trying to fall asleep one night. The code is here. The premise is (I think) much more aptly described by showing intermediate results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://gradybward.com/project/flux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradybward.com/project/flux/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: Check out this data intensive (not recommended for mobile) looping pattern of an attractor with a multi-dimensional parameter orbit.
I saw a blog post by an extremely talented programmer, and was suprised (as he was) to find that there was a natural symmetry to the patterns he was describing. However, in digging into his code, I found that it was not actually symmetrical, but he had just made a very understandable typo which introduced this artificial symmetry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://gradybward.com/project/golog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradybward.com/project/golog/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing a lot more golang of late, so I wrote a (gorgeous) visual debugger for helping to do post-hoc debugging. It&amp;rsquo;s been hugely helpful in my lambda based projects, where one often wants the ability to quickly view &amp;ldquo;what happened during this trace&amp;rdquo; without running locally with a traditional step based debugger.
Unlike many of my projects, this one is pretty well supported, and I&amp;rsquo;ve continued to add features as I need them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://gradybward.com/project/voat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradybward.com/project/voat/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: With a fun algorithm, slight parameter tweaks lead to really different results, as I show in a work based on Elgar&amp;rsquo;s enigma variations.
A good piece of art compells you to understand the process that created it, whether it is the emotion of the composer, or the logic of the painter. A revlation while looking at a piece by Frank Stella made me understand the fundamental mechanism that was generating the work, and gave me confidence that I could recreate it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://gradybward.com/project/voat_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradybward.com/project/voat_2/</guid>
      <description>This project is a work in progress, it still has lots of work to be done.
A few years ago, I created a project called VOAT, in which I used a simple space filling algorithm, alongside a variety of different CSS properties to generate goregeous patterns. I recently revisited this project with the intent on showing folks how it was made, and introducing folks to CSS.
The result is a new site, voat.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>