<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Art on Grady Berry Ward</title>
    <link>http://gradybward.com/tags/art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Art on Grady Berry Ward</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://gradybward.com/tags/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://gradybward.com/project/cindi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradybward.com/project/cindi/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: Janelle Monae&amp;rsquo;s art inspired me to try to build an algorithm that progamatically generates emotion-evoking art, and the results are here.
If you haven’t yet listened to Janelle Monae’s “Metropolis” suite, I highly recommend that you drop the committments you can, pour yourself some coffee and/or wine, and listen to it carefully.
Monae is a magician, a siren, an entertainer, a theorist, a historian, and a visionary. Metropolis helped me understand so much about so much that talking about it here will certainly do it an injustice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://gradybward.com/project/draw_me_css/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradybward.com/project/draw_me_css/</guid>
      <description>In the third Harry Potter book, Harry is given the “Maurauder’s Map”, and one of the many images I like about this map is how the ink spreads outward from the point that it is awoken.
I wondered if you could do this in CSS, so I poked around, learned about CSS Transitions, and came up with a generalized framework for making a set of boxes animate on to the page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://gradybward.com/project/flux/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradybward.com/project/flux/</guid>
      <description>I saw this blog post by an extremely talented programmer, and was suprised (as he was) to find that there was a natural symmetry to the patterns he was describing. However, in digging into his code, I found that it was not actually symmetrical, but he had just made a very understandable typo which introduced this artificial symmetry.
Working with these equations, I found that the surfaces generated by them were gorgeous, and that the surface appeared to be differentiable with respect to every one of the input paramters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://gradybward.com/project/voat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://gradybward.com/project/voat/</guid>
      <description>A good piece of art compells you to understand the process that created it, whether it is the emotion of the composer, or the logic of the painter. A revlation while looking at a piece by Frank Stella made me understand the fundamental mechanism that was generating the work, and gave me confidence that I could recreate it.
Squares (with side of size 1), with two quarter-circles in opposite corners (with radius one-half), in both configurations, with space filling between regions, forms the basis of this work by stella.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>